



Meghashyam THIRUVEEDULA

SUMMARY

IBM Certified Data Scientist hands on experience using Machine Learning in Python technology. Worked on Kaggle, GitHub and hacker Rank projects. Good Knowledge in ML concepts, Data Structure and Algorithms,NLP. Proficient with various IDE like Jupyter-Notebook, Spyder, etc. Handled projects independently and worked with teams as well. Creating mature Data Science pipelines encompassing Data Standardization, Feature extraction, model validation and optimization. Technical assistance to the team for writing SQL queries and in resolving various test challenges. Fluency with Python for Data Science investigations using different libraries such as Numpy, Pandas, Scikit Learn,ML Algorithms.Worked on AWS cloud service-Opensearch, Elastic Search to deploy the model.Hands on experience of DataBricks and NLP.

EXPERIENCE

Designation: AIML Architect

Company: Judge India Solutions, India - Judge Group

Location:Noida, UP, India Duration:Oct 2022- Present

Work:

- Implemented a POC for Airtel payment System, with Python Validations
- Developed a Automation CoE for AIML Team
- SAP ERP connector and implementation of Plant & Chatbot in JK Lakshmi Cement.
- Manpower and Ovality Temperature predictions at Manufacturing Unit to increase productivity, with Azure & AWS opensearch.
- Invest spend Analysis using LLM Model end to end approach.

Designation: Data Scientist Tech Lead Company:HTC Global Services Pvt Ltd, India Location:Hyderabad, Telangana, India Duration:Dec 2021 - Oct 2022

Work:

- Built on Model with MLFlow Experimental Registry.
- Tweet Extractor NLP for Sevita Health services.
- Probability Prediction for Ford GSDB AI project, Product line to supplier, migrated to AWS elastic search
- Redact info specific to files PDF, using pymupdf
- Frosty Flakes client project for DoD -Weather Prediction.

Designation: Data Scientist Technical
Company: PACE Pvt Ltd, India
Location: Hyderabad, Telangana, India
Duration: July 2019 - Dec 2021

Work:

- Building Generalized models to run Drowsiness Detection, local base and cloud- Specialization- OpenCV, also used with AWS open search
- Automation of Image super resolution deployment.
- Built Vehicle Character Recognition provisioning tool to Segmentation onboarding- Specialization- CNN, OpenCV- AWS cloud Open search
- Worked with an Time Series Manufacturing Sales- ARIMA, Monitoring with elastic search.

Designation: Senior ML Engineer

Company: iMindsoft Technologies Pvt Ltd

Location: Chennai, TamilNadu, India Duration: Dec 2011 - June 2019

Work:

- Worked on upstream contributions to various projects. Health Analysis Reviewer and Deployment- Specialization- Pandas
- Worked on building Insurance Prediction, with customer Analysis-Pandas.
- Employee Recognition use case implementation.

Presentations:

Open Data Science - co-ordination at Themes College, Thane

Business Analytics ,Data Science - co-ordination at Villa Marie College, Hyderabad

Proof of Concepts:

Airtel Payment System

Proof of Concept to implement the validation using Python and BOT to develop automation process.

Employee Recognition Management

Proof of Concept to show the centralize change management model for Client

DataBricks With Cloud Service

Proof of Concept to implement Model and execute in DataBricks Platform and their services along with cloud Environment..

Time Series Sales Forecast

Implemented the forecast technique to improve the growth of the manufacture which provided test report for end to end test cases.

Insurance Prediction Dock-ship

- Added support for a new service in for customer to enhance their vehicle insurance cost wise.
- Developed Model to work on,local base and cloud network

CODE PROFILING FOR MACHINE LEARNING

- Developed python module that monitors code and outputs method names with its execution time.
- Created UI that helps display execution times of each method using graphs. Developed module that displays delta code based on git, and differentiates the code which executes.

Certifications:

IBM Certified Data Science Tech

Workshop on Data Science - Teach Tech - IIT Kanpur

Workshop with ISRO - Online Tech -Deep Learning`

Blockchain Technology - IIIT-H

Achievements:

Team of Quarter Award(2023)

Q2 Award is given to contributions made to company in that quarter.

Lead of Quarter Award(2022-2023)

Q1 Award is given to individuals whose performance in the year was beyond expectations and who show exemplary commitment to goals of the company.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS:

Linkedin Profile

https://www.linkedin.com/in/meghashyam-thiruveedula

Github Contributions

https://github.com/Meghashyamt

Overall Opensource Contributions

https://meghashyamt.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

SA Engineering College, Anna University

Bachelor of Engineering — 2006- 2010